Barbie Nation Let's Ride
Barbie Nation
let's ride if you're looking for a solid
way to get a cardio workout in you might
want to take a hard look at the
NordicTrack s27i exercise bike there's
thousands of classes available at your
fingertips on the 27 inch touchscreen
monitor those automatic adjustments that
are going to take place there in the
middle of your workout and a ton of
other features that would have Freddie
Mercury singing about how much he wants
to ride this bike I've been using it for
a while now so I think you guys know the
saying Barbie Nation Let's Ride
what's up everybody it's Jake back once
again in the barbing garage gym and for
today's video I've got the NordicTrack
s27i info review in this video I'm going
to tell you everything you need to know
about this bike from the price some of
the features some of the pros some of
the cons but of course who should or
maybe should not purchase one of these
bad boys but you know before I get going
with all that I have no choice but to
let you know we've reviewed a ton of
exercise bikes on barbin.com so if you
want to browse our best list just go and
search barvin best exercise bikes our
list is going to pull up and you can
find out for yourself which one cracks
at number one spot
okay so let's talk about what I like
about the s27i and honestly I think you
have to talk about the monitor up front
it's a 27 inch touchscreen monitor it's
going to tilt back and forward you know
depending on you know however you want
it to be it's also going to rotate 360
degrees and this is really going to come
in handy especially you know with those
workout classes that are available
through iFit on this monitor that don't
actually require the bike so you know
yoga class a strength training class
whatever it may be you can rotate it you
know do your workout on the ground you
know wherever you want to be in your
home which is really cool there's
automatic incline and decline
adjustments and that's going to be
really nice it's going to happen in the
middle of your workout and it's going to
vary depending on which workout you know
you join but you can also manually
adjust that incline up to 20 or put it
in a decline down to 10 percent with the
resistance you can manually adjust all
the way from zero to 24 different levels
of resistance which is you know a lot to
work with right there there's Bluetooth
capabilities for your headphones and a
heart rate monitor there's a set of
wheels that makes it you know really
easy to move around you have a built-in
fan to cool you off as you start to
sweat there's a built-in water bottle
holder right here on the actual
framework there's popular music loaded
on to the monitor which is really nice
you know it's going to be kind of
entertaining at the same time you know
on top of the already entertaining
classes I also really like the
integration of Google Maps with all of
Nordic tracks equipment you have a 10
year warranty on the framework I mean
guys I could sit here and go on and on
and on so clearly there's a lot to like
about this exercise bike
[Music]
foreign
okay so let's talk about a few potential
cons you may experience with the s27i
let's talk about the monitor first I
think it's great but it's also 27 inches
so it's pretty wide you know you're
going to need a good amount of space
just to house it in your room whatever
room you want it to go in it's also a
pretty expensive bike it's listed right
around twenty five hundred dollars and
on top of that you know high price tag
you're also going to have to pay either
yearly or monthly just for a membership
plan with iFit you also need to have you
know a solid Wi-Fi connection because of
those classes that are you know loaded
onto the monitor there are some times
where you know it's a little slow but
that's because there's over 16 000 that
are available you know there's a lot
loaded on here so you just have to be
patient sometimes and yeah there are a
set of wheels
you know it's going to help you move it
around but it would be nice if there was
some sort of a handle built in right
here that way you don't have to reach
all the way down and grab this framework
you know just to pick it up and move it
around
all right so let's talk about the
pricing now with the s27i it's listed
right around 2500 bucks on the
NordicTrack website and yeah let's be
honest that's pretty expensive for an
exercise bike if you want to stick with
the NordicTrack brand want to save some
money there's a couple cheaper options
available that you might want to check
out but when you compare the price of
this to the rest of the market this is
one of the most expensive options that
are available now there's a lot of
features here there's a lot of luxury
features that you know in turn creates
that you know high price tag and you
know in the long run I think it's going
to be worth it because of those
automatic adjustments all the
trainer-led classes all the you know
your own manual workouts you can create
I mean there's so many cool features
with this exercise bike but 2500 is
still a good chunk of change for an
exercise bike and if you want to save
even more money you know you can find a
much more simple exercise bike out there
that doesn't have the Monitor and all of
that and still get a solid workout in
because of how expensive this bike is
you know you can definitely Finance the
purchase if you need to and I certainly
don't blame you at all NordicTrack it
has a couple different options for you
to work with but this is all going to be
based off of your original purchase so
you know if you want an extended
warranty plan if you want one of those
three yearly options in terms of that
iFit membership that's going to impact
your payments but like I said cool thing
is NordicTrack takes care of all that
for you and lays out all of your options
right there
all right so let's take a second and
talk about the available classes and the
iFit companion app so it's definitely
not a shortage of classes whatsoever
through iFit you have 16
000 different ones to be exact just want
to make sure you heard me correctly the
first time 16
000 different classes available that's a
lot once again you can stream classes
from that iFit companion app which is
really cool directly from your phone so
you know say you're out of town you want
to do a quick yoga class maybe you know
brought a kettlebell or some dumbbells
with you on the road you can bust those
out do a strength training class it's
really cool the companion app also
allows you to track your stats you can
see your past workouts you can you know
check your progress on any challenges
you're trying to complete you can check
out the new ones that are being added
there's so many different things you can
do with that companion app and overall
it's just a really awesome tool
foreign
so now I want to talk about some of the
technology with this high-tech exercise
bike NordicTrack uses Android os9
technology for all their cardio products
right now which is you know really up to
date you know it's pretty fast in terms
of for the most part and it's going to
depend on your Wi-Fi but it's going to
be pretty fast in terms of transitioning
from screen to screen and you know
buffering and loading those workouts
you've got 27 inch touchscreen display
not only does it tilt back and forward
it also rotates 360 degrees so you know
once again if you're going to do one of
those strength training classes or yoga
or whatever it may be you can hop off
the bike you know get positioned
wherever you want rotate that screen to
you and you're all set which is really
cool you have two 30 watt speakers
located just underneath the monitor as
well they produce really solid sound but
because this has Bluetooth capabilities
you can hook up your own headphones if
you want to to you know stream your
workouts that way especially you know if
working out late at night early in the
morning you know what whatever it may be
now you don't have any built-in heart
rate sensors but you can connect your
own heart rate monitor that way you can
track your heart rate variability and
get a really good estimate of how many
calories that you're actually burning as
you're working out which is really nice
you have the integration of Google Maps
which is really cool you know you can go
and create your own workout and kind of
explore the world you know you can go
see all these different cities that you
might not ever really have the chance to
go to you get a sense of you know the
cultural aspects you know a lot of those
workouts that are on here they break
down all of that you know they break
down the architectural side and really
just everything about the city which I'm
a nerd I like that but I think a lot of
you will like that as well you're going
to notice automatic adjustments to your
resistance as well as your incline and
your decline but you can also do that
manually if you want to so with the
resistance you have 24 different levels
for you to use you can also have up to
20 of an incline and down to 10 percent
of a decline clearly you know there's a
lot of tech here with this bike and
honestly it's one of the most high-tech
pieces of equipment that I've ever used
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the mini features you're
going to find with this exercise bike
and I think first of all we've got to
talk about the steel framework it feels
really stable you know I'm not worried
about it you know toppling over as I'm
getting on or off of it it also feels
really durable as well it's about 65
inches tall 57 inches long and about 28
inches wide and it weighs about 217
pounds or so just go ahead and call it
220 why not so that's obviously pretty
heavy so thankfully you do have a set of
wheels on the front to make it pretty
easy to move around your personal space
I just wish there was a designated
handle right here just to make it a
little bit easier on you it does have a
350 pound weight limit which is a really
high number and I really enjoy the fact
that NordicTrack includes a 10 year
warranty on the framework of all of
their cardio equipment now when it comes
to the features I think that touchscreen
monitor is really the thing that pops
out the most you know it's 27 inches
tilt rotate do all that stuff and it's
going to accommodate to your specific
needs which is really nice the
handlebars as well as the seat can be
adjusted for your height which is really
cool too
the pedals right here are compatible
with SPD cleats and cycling shoes so you
know if you are a dedicated cyclist I
think you're going to like that as well
you know you can wear your existing gear
that you have it's really cool I really
like the automatic adjustments that are
going to take place during your workout
you know with your resistance as well as
your incline and your decline but you
know if you need to adjust that on your
own you definitely can do so you have
adjustments located on either side of
your handlebars which definitely come in
handy you also have a push to stop it's
really nice safety feature you know
things are getting out of hand you're
tired whatever the case is just press
that button hold it down everything's
going to stop right away for you you
also have two three pound dumbbells that
are included with your purchase that way
you can get a little pump in as you're
cycling and I also really like how
underneath the framework you have these
little feet I guess you could call them
you know that's what's keeping the bike
stabilized but you know let's say the
room you have your bike sort ins you
know not necessarily even you can lift
the bike up twist on those little feet
and they're going to extend and it's
going to help stabilize that bike even
more
okay so let's go ahead and walk you guys
around the s27 just kind of demo how to
use it for the most part now let's drop
down low really fast this is your motor
for the incline and the decline yes it
makes some noise but it's really not
that bad it's relatively quiet your plug
with this box right here it's a
three-prong Outlet it's gonna go
directly underneath the actual framework
right here and there is a power switch
it's definitely recommended that you
flip that switch off before you whenever
you're done and also you know unplug it
from the outlet just to make sure you
know you don't have any surge issues
your two three pound dumbbells are
located right here on the back and in
terms of adjusting your seat so there's
horizontal adjustments to do that you
twist on this knob and it's going to
allow you to scoot it back scoot It
Forward really whatever is most
comfortable for you and you can also
adjust the height as well same process
you'll unscrew that as you can see that
just dropped on me you can also pull it
back up once again whatever is the most
comfortable for you so move a little
further on down online
here's your water bottle holder it looks
a little small but it definitely expands
a little bit just be careful because
that's plastic and obviously you don't
want to break that your pedals right
here are compatible with SPD cleats and
cycling shoes so all my dedicated
cyclists out there I think you're really
going to like that right here so you're
push to stop
pretty simple right there it's going to
stop everything in its tracks you can
adjust the handlebars same exact process
as over here you're going to untwist
this knob right here and you can either
pull it up or push it right back down
once again whatever is the most
comfortable for you you have your manual
adjustments right here for your
resistance and your incline and declines
pretty simple process I'll go and show
you the incline right here I'm going to
press up
I'm just going to hold it as you can see
it's adjusting all the way up on its own
and it's relatively quiet you know it's
really not that loud
and we're going to Max this bad boy out
right here 20 degree incline that's
pretty solid you know I'm not gonna lie
that's pretty solid let's go ahead and
drop it back down
I'm not gonna go all the way I'm just
gonna go ahead and level it back out for
us here
might be a little bit louder on the
decline but it's still not that loud
you do have your phone tray right here
it's really nice you know you can just
simply set it there and you're good to
go you do have your manual adjustments
for your volume and your built-in fan
speed right here you know it's pretty
simple just press the button it's going
to pop up on the screen and show you
exactly what level it's on now let's
talk about the monitor this thing is
pretty massive as you may see it's
literally a TV it might as well just be
a TV mounted to this bike right here
there's a lot you can do with it I am
having some Wi-Fi difficulty right now
once again you know that does happen
every once in a while in the garage so
that's why I mentioned earlier you got
to have a strong Wi-Fi connection all
right so I'm just going to show you the
home screen right here as you can see
you know it's going to pop up your
workout history it's also going to pull
up the types so treadmill bike rower
elliptical even strength training that's
all going to pop up right here it's
gonna show you your Milestones right
here A bunch of featured classes for you
to choose from I like how it's going to
show you the duration of the actual
workout and also you know how many miles
you're going to be riding so this one's
45 minutes 11 miles that's you know a
nice little workout in itself right
there and then also like you're going to
see the latest from iFit with the
challenges right now and these are
always being updated which is really
nice and it's just the same thing as you
go further on down the line there's just
a ton when it comes to the challenges it
shows you how many different workouts
are in each specific Challenge and it's
also it's kind of like a series I guess
you could call it and that's really cool
now recommended series you can also
Browse by category you can you know act
as if you're in the mountains you'd be
on a road you know there's a lot there's
even Ted Talks right here which is
pretty cool now this is the calendar tab
as I said you know this is kind of you
know giving me some troubles right now
but this is where all your previous
workouts would pop up you can still
click on the create Tab and that's gonna
show you you know right now we're in San
Francisco if I went to browse
here I'll show you I went to browse I'm
gonna go right back to create
boom now we're in Playa del Carmen
Mexico that's pretty cool right it's
gonna do that every single time so it's
always going to switch it up on you you
also got a trophy case right here it's
going to show you any of the challenges
you know I'm in a couple of them right
now you can also discover some more and
that's really nice now you can also do
all of that directly from the companion
app as well all of the stuff down here
at the bottom is going to be right there
for you to use you can also click on the
side right here and pull out this menu
you can switch your profile so cool
thing is I've said this in the other
videos with the NordicTrack equipment
you can have five different profiles
underneath one membership plan with iFit
which is really cool say you know you
got a roommate you got a family member
whatever the case may be even just a
friend you can just go ahead and split
all that up five different ways if you
can
Bluetooth accessories button right here
you can connect everything your Wi-Fi is
here I mean there's a lot of different
stuff right here going on but overall
you know this is a really simple process
I'll go ahead and go to the manual start
just to kind of give you a sense of how
everything looks before every single
workout you are going to have a warm up
you can manually end that if you want to
but it definitely comes in handy in
terms of buffering those classes as
you're doing an instructor you know lead
workout now all of your stats are going
to be right up here so look I'm going to
press the resistance up button it's
going to immediately pop up you know two
three four five and then I'll press it
down and it changes as well now the same
thing with the incline you know as I'm
doing it right here it's going to go up
in 0.5
which is pretty cool we know it's not
going to be too big of a jump for
everybody it's also going to show you
your vertical gain and loss
your estimated calories burned time
elapsed distance traveled all of that
now in your manual workouts I've noticed
you can't really do anything with the
music it actually doesn't play but it's
not that big of a deal if you have your
own headphones in you know you can just
play your own music now it's going to
show you a quarter mile track length and
really it's just going to track all of
your stuff right here now there's also
some other metrics right here it's going
to show your speed your incline and your
resistance so it's not hard to tell that
this is a really high-tech piece of
equipment anybody who is a dedicated
cyclist you know you want a really
awesome way to train at home I think
this is your best bet
foreign
okay so who should purchase the
NordicTrack s27i exercise bike well
anybody who's looking for an exercise
bike that comes with trainer-led classes
I think you're going to really like this
bike right here you know because of that
as well it's going to have those
automatic incline Decline and resistance
adjustments here in the middle of your
workout which I think you're really
going to enjoy and then the 27 inch
touchscreen monitor it's going to make
it feel more immersive as you're working
out and also you know it does rotate at
360 degrees so you can definitely stream
those other workouts that are available
through iFit directly from this monitor
just rotate it and you're good to go
all right so there's three points I got
to mention when it comes to those who
might not want to purchase this bike and
the first one is definitely the money
you know this is available for about
2500 bucks that's a good amount of money
for an exercise bike so if you don't
care about all the luxury features that
are included with this bike you might be
better off with a more basic one and
that kind of leads me next point you
know let's say you're not interested in
streaming your workout classes you don't
really care about that also going to be
better off going for a more basic
exercise bike and last is really just
the space you know it's not the biggest
exercise bike in the world but because
of that 27 inch monitor you're
definitely gonna have to make sure you
have enough space in your home which
that could just be a bit of a hassle
[Music]
that's all I got for you guys today on
the NordicTrack s27i exercise bike I
personally love this thing I think it's
a great option for anyone who's looking
for a high-tech bike that is able to
stream workout classes with instructors
there's automatic adjustments for your
incline Decline and your resistance that
are super helpful you know it is pretty
pricey so it might not be the best
option for every single person out there
thanks for hanging out with me all I
hope this video was really helpful and
that I was able to show you exactly what
to expect with this exercise bike as
always stay tuned for my next video but
for now head over to barbin.com and you
can read more about this product all you
got to do is search bar Bend NordicTrack
s27i exercise bike review and all the
details will be laid out right there for
you I'll catch y'all next time
foreign